前情提要
权力的游戏
You're accused of killing the king.
<i>你被控杀害国王</i>
Except I didn't do it.
但我没杀
Which is why we're having a trial.
所以会有审判
One of my three judges is my father.
三个法官之一是我父亲
Mace Tyrell will serve as the second judge.
梅斯·提利尔是第二位法官
I would like you to be the third.
我希望你来当第三位法官
I will also invite you to sit on the small council.
我还想邀请你加入御前会议
I never realized you had such respect for Dorne, Lord Tywin.
我没想到你这么尊敬多恩，泰温公爵
What good is power
若不能保护心爱之人
if you cannot protect the ones you love?
权力又有何用？
We can avenge them.
可以为他们复仇
You really believe Tyrion murdered your son?
你真的认为是提利昂谋杀你儿子吗？
You're still interested in being queen, I take it?
你还想做王后，对吗？
It would be a great honor.
这是我的荣幸
But I will have to speak to my father about it.
但我要先跟我父亲说
I'll speak to mine.
我也要跟我父亲说
You've started wars to protect this family.
你为保护家族发起战争
What does Tyrion deserve
那么提利昂一把火烧了未来
for lighting that future on fire?
该有怎样的下场？
What kind of Knight beats a helpless girl?
什么骑士会殴打毫无防备的小女孩？
The kind who serves his King.
为国王效力的骑士
The next time Ser Meryn speaks, kill him.
如果马林爵士再说话，就杀了他
How many hands have you betrayed, Pycelle?
你背叛了多少人，派席尔？
I am your loyal servant.
我是您忠诚的仆人
Throw him in one of the black cells.
把他关进黑牢
Oh, no. No, no, no.
不要，不要，不要
There are many who know that without you
有许多人都知道，如果没有您
this city faced certain defeat.
这座城就会被攻陷
The King won't give you any honors,
<i>国王不会授予您任何荣誉</i>
but we will not forget.
但我们不会忘记
The city is yours.
这座城是您的
All these people, they're your subjects now.
<i>所有人现在都是您的臣民</i>
Sometimes it is better to answer injustice
有时用仁慈对待不公
with mercy.
会更好
I will answer injustice with justice.
我会用公正对待不公
In the box you'll find a special gift--
<i>盒子里有一件特殊的礼物</i>
Theon's favorite toy.
是席恩最喜欢的玩具
He cried when I took it away from him.
我把它拿走时他哭了
I'm going to pick the fastest ship in our fleet.
我会带上舰队里最快的船
and I'm going to bring him home.
<i>我会带他回家</i>
We need to look east for ships and men.
我们要向东寻找船和人
Soldiers win wars.
是士兵赢得战争
We don't have any gold.
我们没有金子了
I'm running out of time, Ser Davos.
我没时间了，戴佛斯爵士
Which means you're running out of time.
意味着你也没时间了
-=TLF字幕组=- 荣誉出品
翻译：Hello_Agnes
翻译：思文不是喵
翻译：lydia萌
君临
King's Landing
翻译&校对：LordVader
特效：飞翔的鸡
统筹：饭离烨
恐怖堡
Dreadfort
临冬城
WinterFell
绝境长城
The Wall
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权力的游戏
第四季   第六集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
布莱恩·克格曼
导演
埃里克·萨哈洛夫
人神律法
Your Grace, if you'd like to sit, I'm sure that--
陛下，如果您想坐下，我相信…
We've been here since midday.
我们中午就到了
Easterners have a difference sense of time, I've often found.
东方人时间观念不同，我早就发现了
Once I was waiting for Salladhor Saan here in Braavos.
有一次我在布拉佛斯等萨拉多·桑恩
Together, we were going to run
我们总共要运…
three shiploads of the finest--
三船最好的…
Welcome to the Iron Bank.
欢迎来到铁金库
Please, sit.
请坐
What can we do for you, Lord Stannis?
有什么能为您效劳的，史坦尼斯大人？
This is Stannis of the House Baratheon,
这位是拜拉席恩家族的史坦尼斯
King of the Andals and the First Men,
<i>安达尔人和先民的国王</i>
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
七国之王和全境守护者
The Iron Throne is currently occupied
<i>铁王座现在属于</i>
by Tommen of the House Baratheon,
拜拉席恩家族的托曼
King of the Andals and the First Men,
安达尔人和先民的国王
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
七国之王和全境守护者
He shares no blood with me.
他和我没有血缘关系
He is a bastard born of incest.
他是乱伦出生的私生子
As was his brother before him.
<i>和他哥哥一样</i>
Yes, we have heard this story.
是的，我们听过这个故事
It's not a story. It's the truth.
这不是故事，这是事实
The king's grandfather tells a different story.
国王祖父讲的故事不同于此
A story about a jealous uncle
那是关于一个嫉妒的叔叔
whose attempts to usurp the throne from the rightful king
企图从合法的国王手中篡夺王位
cost the Seven Kingdoms dearly in blood and gold.
使七国付出了沉重的血和黄金的代价
Gold you loaned him.
你借给他的黄金
And you feel your blood gives you a claim on our gold?
你认为你的血统能让你从我们这儿拿走黄金？
More than any man living.
比其他在世的人都有资格
Across the Narrow Sea, your books are filled
狭海对面，你的评价都是
with words like "usurper" and "madman"
“篡位者”，“疯子”
and "blood right."
和“正统”
Here, our books are filled with numbers.
在这里，我们都以数字说话
We prefer the stories they tell.
我们更喜欢他们讲的故事
More plain.
更直接
Less open to interpretation.
更明了
How many fighting men remain loyal to you?
还有多少战士仍忠于你？
4,000.
And how many ships do you have?
<i>你有多少船只？</i>
The ones still afloat, Ser Davos,
<i>还在海上的，戴佛斯爵士</i>
not at the bottom of Blackwater Bay.
不在黑水湾的
32.
32艘
And how much wheat and barley and beef
你们龙石岛上能生产多少
and pork do you produce on Dragonstone
小麦，大麦，牛肉和猪肉
to feed your 4,000 men on your 32 ships?
来喂饱你32艘船上的4000名战士？
None.
没有
You can see why these numbers seem unlikely to add up
你知道为什么在我们看来
to a happy ending from our perspective.
这些数字不会再增长了吧
I'm afraid we must respectfully
<i>恐怕我们不得不恭敬地</i>
decline your request.
<i>拒绝你们的请求了</i>
But we thank you for paying us the honor of your visit.
<i>但我们感谢你们前来拜访</i>
My lord.
大人
I'm not a lord, Ser Davos Seaworth.
我不是大人，戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士
You would not be either here.
你也不能待在这里
In Braavos,
在布拉佛斯
thieves are not rewarded with titles.
小偷不能获得封号
Well, strictly speaking, I didn't do the thieving.
严格来说，我没有偷东西
That would be the pirates.
是海盗干的
I just moved what they stole from one place to another.
我只是把他们偷的东西移了位置
This is the payment that was demanded
这是史坦尼斯国王因为我的罪行
by King Stannis for my crimes.
要求我付出的代价
I consider it an honest accounting.
我视之为诚实的理由
He's an honest man and he's your best chance
他是个诚实的人，他是您拿回
to get back the money you've sunk into Westeros.
在维斯特洛损失的钱最好的选择
Which is a lot, I imagine. Wars are expensive.
我想应该有很多吧，打仗很花钱
The war is over.
战争结束了
As long as Stannis lives, the war is not over.
只要史坦尼斯还活着，战争就不会结束
Who's the real power in King's Landing?
君临真正的权力在谁手上？
- Ser Davos... - Humor me.
- 戴佛斯爵士…
- 回答我
- Tywin Lannister. - How old is Tywin Lannister?
- <i>泰温·兰尼斯特</i>
- 泰温·兰尼斯特多大岁数了？
67.
67. And when he dies, who's in command?
67，他死后谁会掌权？
A half-grown boy,
一个毛头小子
the product of incest?
<i>乱伦的私生子？</i>
Cersei Lannister, a queen whose people despise her?
瑟曦·兰尼斯特，受子民鄙视的太后？
Jaime Lannister, a man best known for killing the king
詹姆·兰尼斯特，一个以谋杀他发誓保护的国王
he was sworn to protect?
<i>闻名的人？</i>
When Tywin's gone, who do you back?
泰温死后你支持谁？
That is a problem for another time.
这个问题以后解决
Begging your pardon, I think it's a problem for now.
恕我直言，我认为这个问题现在就得解决
There's only one reliable leader left in Westeros.
维斯特洛只有一位值得信赖的领导者了
Stannis.
史坦尼斯
He's got the birthright.
他有继承权
He's in his prime.
正当壮年
He's a tried and tested battle commander.
他是个身经百战的指挥官
And he doesn't just talk about paying people back,
他说报答不是说说而已
he does it.
他会付出行动
The lookout sees a pirate ship sailing their way.
<i>瞭望员看到一艘海盗船朝他们驶来</i>
The captain shouts to his first mate,
<i>船长朝大副喊道</i>
"Bring me my red shirt."
“把我的红衣拿来”
The first mate brings the red shirt and the captain puts it on.
大副拿来红衣，船长穿上
And when the pirates try to board,
海盗上岸时
the brave captain leads his men to victory.
勇敢的船长带领船员打了胜仗
A few days later, the lookout screams,
几天后，瞭望员大喊
"Two pirate ships!"
“两艘海盗船！”
The crew is shivering like scared mice.
船员们吓得瑟瑟发抖
But the courageous captain hollers,
但勇敢的船长喊道
"Bring me my red shirt!"
“把我的红衣拿来！”
After the battle, the first mate asks,
<i>战后，大副问道</i>
"Captain, why do you call for your red shirt before battle?"
“船长，为什么你战前都要穿上红衣？”
The captain replies,
船长回答
"So that if I am stabbed, you will not see me bleed."
“这样万一我被刺，你们就看不到我流血了”
The next morning the lookout screams,
第二天早上，瞭望员大喊
"10 pirate ships!
“十艘海盗船！”
We are surrounded!"
“我们被包围了！”
The crew goes silent.
<i>船员们沉默了</i>
They all look to their brave captain,
<i>他们看着勇敢的船长</i>
waiting for his usual command.
<i>等着他往常下达的指令</i>
Calm as ever, the captain bellows...
<i>镇定如常，船长喊道</i>
"Bring me my brown pants!"
“把我的棕色裤子拿来！”
You think they ever met a pirate who didn't tell them that joke?
你认为他们遇到过不讲这个笑话的海盗？
Davos.
戴佛斯
I heard you were rotting in a dungeon in Dragonstone.
我听说你在龙石岛的地牢里腐烂了
Only half rotted.
只腐烂了一半
Join us, my friend. Join us.
一起来，朋友，一起来
This is Lhara.
这是劳拉
- And this is-- - I am Lhara.
- 这是…
- 我才是劳拉
She's an artist, this one, truly.
她是个艺术家，这位，真的
No time, I'm afraid. We sail at sunrise.
恐怕没时间了，我们日出启程
We?
我们？
You, me-- we.
你，我…我们
Once I thought this man loved me.
曾经我以为这个男人爱我
Now I know he despises me.
<i>现在我知道他鄙视我</i>
He wants to see me die poor and alone on some cold--
他想看我孤独贫穷地死在寒冷…
You won't be alone.
你不会孤独
And you won't be poor.
也不会贫穷
There's a chest of the good stuff left back at your house.
你家里有一箱好东西
I gave it to your wife.
我给你妻子了
You're not my friend, my friend.
你不是我朋友，我的朋友
I'll see you at sunrise.
日出见
"I give you until the full moon
“我限你们满月前”
to order all ironborn scum out of the North
“命令铁民离开北境”
and back to those shit-stained rocks you call home.
<i>“回到你们那肮脏不堪的家”</i>
On the first night of the full moon,
“满月的第一夜”
I will hunt down every islander still on our lands
“我会猎杀所有还未离开的岛民”
and flay them living,
“活剥他们的皮”
the way I flayed the 20 ironborn scum
“就像我活剥在临冬城发现的”
I found at Winterfell.
“那20个铁民”
In the box you'll find a special gift--
<i>“你们会在盒子里发现一份特殊的礼物…”</i>
Theon's favorite toy.
<i>“席恩最爱的玩物”</i>
He cried when I took it away from him.
<i>“我拿走时他哭了”</i>
Leave the North now or more boxes will follow
<i>“马上离开北境，否则将有更多盒子奉上”</i>
with more Theon.
<i>“更多席恩”</i>
Signed Ramsay Snow,
<i>“拉姆斯·雪诺上”</i>
natural born son of Roose Bolton,
<i>“卢斯·波顿的亲生子”</i>
Lord of the Dreadfort
<i>“恐怖堡领主”</i>
and Warden of the North."
<i>“北境守护者”</i>
Yes!
爽！
They skinned our countrymen
<i>他们剥了我们同胞的皮</i>
and they mutilated my brother,
<i>搞残了我的弟弟</i>
your prince.
<i>你们的王子</i>
Your prince.
Everything they've done to him,
<i>他们对他做的一切</i>
they've also done to you.
<i>也对你们做了</i>
Yes! Yes!
爽！爽！
As long as they can hurt our prince with impunity,
<i>只要他们残害我们的王子还不受惩罚</i>
the word ironborn means nothing.
<i>铁民一词就一文不值</i>
Go left.
左边
- Theon Greyjoy. - I don't know--
- 席恩·葛雷乔伊
- 我不知道…
I'm here for Theon Greyjoy.
我来找席恩·葛雷乔伊
Take me to the dungeons.
带我去地牢
He's not in the dungeons.
他不在地牢
- Last cage on the right. - Thank you.
- 右边最后一间
- 谢谢
This way!
<i>这边！</i>
We're going home.
我们回家
No!
不！
It's all right. It's me, Yara.
没事的，是我，亚拉
You can't trick me.
你骗不了我
Tell him. Tell him you couldn't trick me.
告诉他，告诉他你骗不了我
I'm not tricking you, Theon. I'm saving you.
我没骗你，席恩，我在救你
Not Theon! Reek!
不是席恩！是臭佬！
- Reek! My name is Reek! - They're here.
- 臭佬，我叫臭佬！
<i>- 他们来了</i>
If they catch us in here, we're trapped.
如果他们在这里抓到我们，我们就被困住了
Help me with him.
帮我拉他起来
No, you can't!
不，不能这样！
- You can't! - You're Theon Greyjoy.
- 你们不能这样！
- 你是席恩·葛雷乔伊
No, I don't believe her! I know who I am!
不，我不相信她！我知道我是谁！
I'm Reek! Reek! Loyal Reek!
我是臭佬！臭佬！忠诚的臭佬！
Good Reek! I've always been Reek!
好臭佬！我永远是臭佬！
This is turning into a lovely evening.
今晚将会非常美好
I'm Reek!
<i>我是臭佬！</i>
Loyal Reek!
忠诚的臭佬！
Aah! Theon!
席恩！
Give me my brother and no more of your men will die.
把我弟弟还给我，就不会再有人死
You've got bigger balls than he ever did.
你的胆子比他大
But with those big balls of yours...
不过胆子这么大…
how fast can you run?
你能跑多快？
Make for the ship, now.
开船，快
But your brother.
可你弟弟
My brother is dead.
我弟弟已经死了
I have a treat for you.
我有好东西给你
A reward.
奖赏
Reward?
奖赏？
Yes, Reek.
是的，臭佬
Those creatures who came in the night,
昨晚来的那些人
they wanted to take you away.
他们想把你带走
And you didn't let them.
你没跟他们走
You remained loyal.
你很忠诚
I-- I didn't want them to take me.
我…我不想他们带我走
I was so scared.
我很害怕
- I didn't want them-- - Yes, yes, Reek.
- 我不想让他们…
- 是的，是的，臭佬
It's a bath.
洗澡
For you.
特为你准备的
Remove those rags.
快换下这身脏东西
Now.
就现在
The britches, too, Reek.
裤子也是，臭佬
Take them off.
把它们脱了
Do you love me, Reek?
你喜欢我么，臭佬？
Yes, of course, my lord.
是的，当然了，大人
Good.
好的
Because I need you to do something for me.
我需要你为我做点事情
Something very important.
很重要的事情
There's a castle, you see.
有座城堡
Some bad men hold this castle.
一个坏人掌控着它
I need your help to take this castle back.
我需要你帮助，把城堡夺回来
But how can--
要怎么才…
I need you to play a role.
我需要你扮演个角色
To pretend to be someone you're not.
假装成别人
Pretend to be who?
假装成谁？
Theon Greyjoy.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
你面对的是坦格里安家族的“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝…
一世…
不焚者…
弥林的女王…
安达尔人和先民的女王…
大草海的卡丽熙
奴隶解放者和龙之母
别害怕，我的朋友
女王说，你可以上前说话
He is a goatherd.
他是个牧羊人
He says he prayed for your victory against the slave masters.
他说他为您打破镣铐的胜利而祝福
I thank him for his prayers.
我非常感谢他的祝福
It was your dragons, he says.
这是您的龙所做的，他说
They came this morning for his flock.
它们早上找到了他的羊群
He hopes he has not offended Your Grace,
他希望他没有冒犯您的圣誉
but now he has nothing.
但是现在他一无所有了
Tell this man I am sorry for his hardship.
告诉他，我对他的困境感到抱歉
I cannot bring back his goats,
但我不能把他的羊弄回来
but I will see he is paid their value three times over.
赔偿给他三倍价值的东西
Send the next one in.
让下一个进来
高贵的西茨达拉·左·洛拉克请求觐见女王
高贵的西茨达拉·左·洛拉克可以自己跟我讲话
Queen Daenerys.
丹妮莉丝女王
Tales of your beauty were not exaggerated.
您的美貌，果真名不虚传
I thank you.
谢谢夸奖
Mine is one of the oldest and proudest families in Meereen.
我是弥林最高贵最古老的家族之一
Then it is my honor to receive you.
接见您真是我的荣幸
My father, one of Meereen's most respected
我的父亲，弥林最受尊重…
and beloved citizens, oversaw the restoration
和爱戴的人，负责修复…
and maintenance of its greatest landmarks.
和维护伟大的古迹
This pyramid included.
包括金字塔
For that, he has my gratitude.
对此我心存感激
I should be honored to meet him.
我应该亲自接见他
You have, Your Grace.
您已经见过了，殿下
You crucified him.
您用十字架钉死了他
I pray you'll never live to see
我希望您永远不会见到
a member of your family treated so cruelly.
家族成员被如此残忍处死的情景
Your father crucified innocent children.
你父亲残忍地钉死过多少无辜儿童
My father spoke out against crucifying those children.
我父亲公开反对过如此对待儿童
He decried it as a criminal act, but was overruled.
他明确指出这即是犯罪行为，但他被驳斥了
Is it justice to answer one crime with another?
这样以怨报怨是正确的吗？
I am sorry you no longer have a father,
我非常抱歉您失去了父亲
but my treatment of the masters was no crime.
但我对奴隶主的处置是没有错误的
You'd be wise to remember that.
你最好明白这一点
What's done is done.
事已至此，谁都不能改变
You are the queen and I am a servant of Meereen.
您是女王，而我是弥林的仆人
A servant who does not wish to see its traditions eradicated.
一个不希望看到传统文化被根除的仆人
And what traditions do you speak of?
你所说的传统是什么呢？
The tradition of funeral rite.
传统丧葬仪式
Proper burial in the Temple of the Graces.
体面地葬在神殿之下
My father and 162 noble Meereenese
我的父亲以及162位弥林贵族
are still nailed to those posts,
仍被钉子路边
carrion for vultures, rotting in the sun.
被秃鹰啃食着，腐烂在烈日之下
Your Grace, I ask that you order these men taken down
陛下，我请求您命人把他们释放下来
so that they might receive proper burials.
还他们个体面的葬礼
And what of the slave children these noble Meereenese crucified?
那些被贵族钉死的奴隶的孩子呢？
They were rotting in the sun as well.
他们也在烈日下腐烂
Would you have begged me for their right to a proper burial?
你怎么不求我给他们以体面地丧葬仪式
Your Grace, I cannot defend the actions of the masters.
陛下，我不能抵抗大人们的命令
I can only speak to you as a son who loved his father.
我只能以一个深爱父亲的儿子的身份请求您
Let me take his body down.
求您放下他的躯体
Let me have him brought to the temple
让我把他带回神殿
and buried with dignity
让他有尊严的下葬
so that he might find peace in the next world.
让他在另个世界得以安宁
Bury your father, Hizdahr zo Loraq.
安葬你的父亲吧，西茨达拉·左·洛拉克
Thank you, my queen.
谢谢您，我的女王
How many more?
还有多少人？
There are 212 supplicants waiting, Your Grace.
还有212个上访者在等待
212?
212个？
Send the next one in.
让下个进来
These meetings aren't always going to be this early, are they?
这些会议不总是这么早开，对吧？
I was up late last night.
我昨天睡得可很晚
So, does this mean I am a master of something now?
是说，我现在也是个大人之类的吗？
Coins, ships?
金币，船只？
Lord Tywin and I already determined
泰温大人和我已经决定
that I shall be the Master of Ships long before you--
由我来管理船只而不是你
Lord Tywin, it's a great honor
泰温大人，这真是我的荣幸
to have been granted a seat on this council. I--
在议会有一席之地
The trial begins this afternoon.
审判在下午举行
We only have the morning for affairs of state.
我们只在早上有空处理国事
Shall we begin?
可以开始了吗？
Sandor Clegane has been spotted in the Riverlands, my lord.
有人在河间地看到了桑铎·克里冈，大人
A coward and a traitor.
一个懦夫，叛国贼
My birds tell me the Hound slaughtered five of our soldiers.
我的小鸟告诉我猎狗杀了我们五个士兵
I believe the phrase "fuck the king" was uttered.
他的原话是“去他妈的国王”
Disgraceful.
大胆
What would it take to make the common soldier
多少钱能让个普通士兵
stupid enough to try his luck with the Hound?
傻到去挑战猎狗
10 silver stags seems a generous bounty.
10个银币应该算慷慨了
Make it 100. What else?
那就100个，还有别的吗？
More whispers from the east, my lord.
有流言从东部传来
The Targaryen girl?
那个坦格利安姑娘
Daenerys has taken up residence in Meereen.
丹妮莉丝已经驻扎在弥林了
She has conquered the city and rules as its queen.
她攻下了那座城，自封为女王
Conquered with what?
拿什么攻下的？
She commands an army of Unsullied, my queen.
>她率领着无垢者大军，殿下
Some 8,000 strong.
8000个勇士
She has a company of sellswords--
佣兵无数
the Second Sons.
次子军团
She has two knights advising her--
他还有两个骑士来引导她
Jorah Mormont and Barristan Selmy.
乔拉·莫尔蒙和巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
And she has three dragons.
还有三条龙
Baby dragons.
小龙
Larger every year, Your Grace.
每年都在长大，陛下
Mormont is spying on her for us.
莫尔蒙为我们监视着她
No longer. He appears to be fully devoted to her.
没有了，他现在一心为她效劳
As for Ser Barristan, it would seem
至于巴利斯坦爵士
he took his dismissal from the Kingsguard
看起来他被踢出御林铁卫…
a bit harder than anticipated.
怨气超出我们的预料
He's an old man.
他已经老了
He wasn't fit to protect my son.
不适合保护我的儿子
Joffrey didn't die on his watch.
乔佛里没在他的看护下死去
Dismissing him was as insulting as it was stupid.
把他解职既无礼又愚蠢
Don't tell me you're worried about a child halfway across the world.
别告诉我你很担心世界另一头的那个孩子
A child with two seasoned warriors counseling her
这个孩子，有个阅历丰富的勇士为她参谋
and a powerful army at her back, Your Grace.
身后有雄壮的军队，殿下
Lord Varys is right.
瓦里斯大人说得对
I have been to Essos and seen the Unsullied firsthand.
我去过厄斯索斯，亲眼见过无垢者
They are very impressive on the battlefield.
他们在战场上令人瞠目
Less so in the bedroom.
床上却不行
Dragons haven't won a war in 300 years.
300年来龙都未赢过战争
Armies win them all the time.
只有军队才行
She must be dealt with.
对她一定要有所行动
How, my lord?
如何行动，大人？
By force?
用武力？
Eventually, if it comes to that.
如果迫不得已，终归如此
Can your little birds find their way into Meereen?
你的小鸟可以到弥林吗？
Most certainly, my Lord Hand.
当然可以，首相大人
Mmm. Lord Tyrell, be a good man.
提利尔大人，帮我个忙
Fetch my quill and paper.
<i>拿我的笔和纸来</i>
Prince Oberyn.
奥柏伦亲王
Lord Varys...
瓦里斯大人…
Only Varys. I'm not actually a nobleman.
叫我瓦里斯就行，我其实不是贵族
No one is under obligation to call me lord.
没必要叫我大人
And yet everyone does.
但人人都这么叫
You seem quite knowledgeable about the Unsullied.
你好像很了解无垢者
Did you spend much time in Essos?
你在厄斯索斯待过很久吗？
Five years.
五年
May I ask why?
能问问您是去做什么吗？
'Tis a big and beautiful world.
瓦兰提斯辽阔美丽
Most of us live and die
大多数人生老病死
in the same corner where we were born
都在自己出生的小地方
and never get to see any of it.
从没机会去瓦兰提斯
I don't want to be most of us.
我不想跟大多数人一样
Most of us aren't princes.
大多数人都不是亲王
You are from Essos.
你，是从厄斯索斯来的
Where? Lys?
哪里？里斯？
I have an ear for accents.
<i>我能听出来口音</i>
I've lost my accent entirely.
我已经完全没有口音了
I have an ear for that as well.
那我也能听出来
How did you get here?
<i>你怎么会来这？</i>
It's a long story.
说来话长
One you don't like telling people.
你不喜欢告诉别人
People I trust.
只告诉信任的人
My paramour Ellaria, she would find you very interesting.
我的情人艾拉莉亚肯定会觉得你很有趣
You should come to the brothel and meet her.
你应该来妓院见见她
We brought our own wine, not the swill they serve here.
我们带了自家的酒，这的酒像泔水似的
We have some lovely boys on retainer, but...
我们有几个家仆是漂亮男孩，不过…
You did like boys before?
你以前喜欢男孩吧？
Really?
真的？
Girls? Hmm.
喜欢女的？嗯
I hope you won't be offended when I say I never would have guessed.
但愿你别介意，我真是没想到
Not at all.
完全不会
But I was never interested in girls, either.
但我对女的也没兴趣
- What then? - Nothing.
- 那对什么有兴趣？
- <i>没有</i>
Everybody is interested in something.
每个人都有兴趣的
Not me.
<i>我就没有</i>
When I see what desire does to people,
当我见到欲望把人变成了什么样
what it's done to this country,
把这个国家变成了什么样之后
I am very glad to have no part in it.
我很高兴我没有
Besides, the absence of desire
<i>而且，没有欲望</i>
leaves one free to pursue other things.
就可以自由追求别的东西
Such as?
比如？
Let me guess, I've been pardoned.
让我猜猜，我被赦免了
Really?
不是吧？
Father's orders.
父亲的命令
Well, we mustn't disappoint Father.
我们可不能让父亲失望
Kingslayer!
<i>弑君者！</i>
I, Tommen of the House Baratheon,
我，拜拉席恩家族的
First of my Name,
<i>托曼一世</i>
King of the Andals and the First Men,
安达尔人和先民的国王
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms,
七大王国的王
do hereby recuse myself from this trial.
在此宣布退出审判
Tywin of the House Lannister, Hand of the King,
由首相，王国的守护者
Protector of the Realm, will sit as judge in my stead.
兰尼斯特家族的泰温，代我担任法官
And with him Prince Oberyn of the House Martell
另外两位法官是马泰尔家族的奥柏伦亲王
and Lord Mace of the House Tyrell.
<i>和提利尔家族的梅斯公爵</i>
And if found guilty...
若判决有罪…
may the gods punish the accused.
愿诸神惩罚被告人
Tyrion of the House Lannister,
兰尼斯特家族的提利昂
you stand accused by the Queen Regent of regicide.
你被摄政太后控告弑君
Did you kill King Joffrey?
你是否杀害乔佛里国王？
No.
没有
Did your wife, the Lady Sansa?
是你妻子珊莎夫人杀的吗？
Not that I know of.
就我所知不是
How would you say he died, then?
那你认为他是如何死的？
Choked on his pigeon pie.
被鸽子派噎着了
So you would blame the bakers?
那你是怪厨子？
Or the pigeons. Just leave me out of it.
或是鸽子，总之与我无关
The crown may call its first witness.
国王要求传召第一位证人
Once we'd got King Joffrey safely away
我们刚把乔佛里国王从暴民中
from the mob, the Imp rounded on him.
安全救出，小恶魔就责骂他
He slapped the king across the face
他扇了国王的嘴巴
and called him a vicious idiot and a fool.
骂他是邪恶愚蠢的傻瓜
It wasn't the first time the Imp threatened Joffrey.
<i>这不是小恶魔第一次威胁乔佛里了</i>
Right here in this throne room,
就在这，在这个王座大厅里
he marched up those steps and called our king a halfwit.
他走上了那些台阶，骂国王是蠢货
Compared His Grace to the Mad King
<i>将乔佛里陛下比作疯王</i>
and suggested he'd meet the same fate.
<i>咒他会落得相同下场</i>
And when I spoke in the king's defense,
当我帮国王说话时
he threatened to have me killed.
他威胁说要处死我
Oh, why don't you tell them what Joffrey was doing?
噢，你怎么不说说乔佛里在干嘛？
- Silence. - Pointing a loaded crossbow at Sansa Stark
<i>- 安静</i>
- 他拿上箭的弩瞄着珊莎·史塔克
while you tore at her clothes and beat her.
而你正在扒她衣服打她
Silence!
安静！
You will not speak unless called upon.
不经允许你不许讲话
You're dismissed, Ser Meryn.
你下去吧，马林爵士
Basilisk venom,
石蜥毒
widow's blood,
寡妇之血
wolfsbane,
附子草
essence of nightshade,
龙葵精华
sweetsleep,
甜睡花
tears of Lys,
里斯之泪
demon's dance...
鬼舞草
blind eye--
盲眼…
I think you have made your point, Grand Maester.
我认为你已说明白了，大学士
You have a lot of poison in your store.
你的储藏室有许多毒药
Had, Prince Oberyn.
<i>是以前有，</i>奥柏伦亲王
My stores were plundered.
我的储藏都被掠夺了
By whom?
被谁？
By the accused, Tyrion Lannister,
<i>被告者，提利昂·兰尼斯特</i>
after he had me wrongfully imprisoned.
在他把我无理关押之后
Grand Maester,
<i>大学士</i>
you examined King Joffrey's corpse.
你检查了乔佛里国王的尸体
Was it without question poison that killed him?
是否确信无疑是毒药致死的？
Without question.
确信无疑
This was found on the body of Dontos Hollard,
这是在国王的弄臣，唐托斯·霍拉德的
the king's fool.
尸体上发现的
He was last seen spiriting Sansa Stark,
最后被人看见时，他正带着珊莎·史塔克
the wife of the accused, away from the feast.
被告者的妻子，从婚宴上逃走
She wore this necklace
她在婚宴那天
the day of the wedding.
<i>戴着这条项链</i>
Residue of a most rare
<i>其中检测出一种</i>
and terrible poison was found inside.
最罕见、最可怕的毒药残渣
Was this one of the poisons stolen from your store?
是从你储藏室偷走的毒药之一吗？
It was. The Strangler.
是的，是“扼死者”
A poison few in the Seven Kingdoms possess.
七大王国内十分少有的毒药
And used to strike down the most noble child
却被用来毒害诸神带到世间的
the gods ever put on this good earth.
最高尚的孩子
"I will hurt you for this.
<i>“我会为此伤害你”</i>
A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
<i>“总有一天，当你自以为平安幸福时”</i>
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth
“喜悦会在口中化成灰烬”
and you will know the debt is paid."
“到那时候，你将明白债已偿还”
Your own brother said this to you?
你亲弟弟对你说这话？
Shortly before the Battle of Blackwater Bay.
就在黑水湾战役不久前
I confronted him about his plans to put Joffrey on the front lines.
我质问他为何把乔佛里安排到前线
As it turned out, when the attack came,
结果，当敌人来袭之时
Joff insisted on remaining at the battlements.
小乔要坚守在城垛
He believed his presence would inspire the troops.
他坚信他在场能够鼓舞士气
Tyrion said,
提利昂说
"And you will know the debt is paid."
“到那时候，你将明白债已偿还”
What debt?
什么债？
I discovered he'd been keeping whores
我发现了他在首相塔里
in the Tower of the Hand.
养着妓女的事
I asked him to confine his salacious acts
我让他约束好自己
to the brothel where such behavior belongs.
<i>淫乱行为到妓院去搞，那才是淫乱的地方</i>
He wasn't pleased.
他很不满
Thank you, Your Grace,
谢谢您，殿下
for the courage of your testimony.
感谢您勇于作证
Do you remember the precise nature of this threat?
<i>你还记得这次威胁的准确用词吗？</i>
I'm afraid I do, my lord.
<i>我记得，大人</i>
He said, "Perhaps you should speak more softly to me, then.
<i>他说：“那你跟我说话得再客气点”</i>
Monsters are dangerous
“怪物很危险的”
and just now kings are dying like flies."
“而且最近国王们可是命如蝼蚁”
And he said this to you at a meeting of the small council?
他在御前会议上对你说了这话？
Yes.
是的
After we received word of Robb Stark's death.
在我们收到罗柏·史塔克死了的消息之后
He didn't seem gladdened by the news.
他听到消息似乎并不开心
Perhaps his marriage to Sansa Stark
也许他与珊莎·史塔克的婚姻
had made him more sympathetic to the northern cause.
使他开始同情北境的暴动
You're excused, Lord Varys.
你可以离开了，瓦里斯大人
Father, may I ask the witness one question?
父亲，我能否问证人一个问题？
One.
就一个
You once said
你曾说过
that without me, this city would have faced certain defeat.
如果没有我，这座城必将陷落
You said the histories would never mention me,
你说过历史永远不会提到我
but you would not forget.
但你不会忘记
Have you forgotten, Lord Varys?
难道你忘了吗，瓦里斯大人？
Sadly, my lord,
很不幸，大人
I never forget a thing.
我从不会忘记任何事
We will adjourn for now.
暂时休庭
Toll the bells in an hour's time.
一小时后鸣钟
Clear the court!
<i>退席！</i>
You'd condemn your own son to death?
<i>你想给亲生儿子判死罪？</i>
I've condemned no one. The trial is not over.
我还没判刑，审判还没完
This isn't a trial. It's a farce.
这哪是审判，就是胡闹
Cersei has manipulated everything and you know it.
你明知瑟曦在幕后操纵了一切
I know nothing of the sort.
我对此类事情毫不知情
- You've always hated Tyrion. - He killed his king.
- 你一直恨提利昂
- 他杀了国王
As did I.
我也杀了
Do you know the last order the Mad King gave me?
你知道疯王对我下的最后一个命令是什么？
To bring him your head.
<i>向他献上你的首级</i>
I saved your life so you could murder my brother?
我救你的命是为了让你谋杀我弟弟吗？
- It won't be murder. It'll be justice. - Justice?
- 不是谋杀，一切都是公正的
- 公正？
I'm performing my sworn duty as Hand of the King.
我在履行国王之手宣誓的职责
If Tyrion is found guilty, he will be punished accordingly.
如果提利昂被认定有罪，他会受到相应的惩罚
- He'll be executed. - No, he'll be punished accordingly.
- 他会被处决
- 不，是相应的惩罚
Once you said family is what lives on.
你曾说过，家族是生命的意义所在
All that lives on.
一切的意义所在
You told me about a dynasty that would last 1,000 years.
你跟我说，王朝是千秋基业
What happens to your dynasty when Tyrion dies?
提利昂如果死了，你的王朝会怎样？
I'm a Kingsguard,
我是御林铁卫
forbidden by oath to carry on the family line.
我的誓言禁止我延续家族血脉
I'm well aware of your oath.
我很清楚你的誓言
What happens to your name?
你的名号会怎样？
Who carries the lion banner into future battles?
谁在未来的战斗中扛起狮子大旗？
Your nephews?
你侄儿们？
Lancel Lannister?
蓝赛尔·兰尼斯特？
Others whose names I don't even remember?
还是其他我连名字都不记得的人？
What happens to my dynasty if I spare the life of my grandson's killer?
我饶恕了杀我外孙的凶手，我的王朝会怎样？
It survives through me.
由我来延续
I'll leave the Kingsguard.
我离开御林铁卫
I'll take my place as your son and heir
我会承担你的儿子和继承人的职责
if you let Tyrion live.
只要你放过提利昂
Done.
好
When the testimony's concluded and a guilty verdict rendered,
举证结束，判决会宣布有罪
Tyrion will be given the chance to speak.
提利昂有机会讲话
He'll plead for mercy. I'll allow him to join the Night's Watch.
他会请求免死，我会允许他加入守夜人
In three days' time, he'll depart for Castle Black
<i>三天内，他必须前往黑城堡</i>
and live out his days at the Wall.
<i>在长城度过余生</i>
You'll remove your white cloak immediately.
<i>你将立即脱下白袍</i>
You will leave King's Landing
<i>离开君临城</i>
to assume your rightful place at Casterly Rock.
<i>在凯岩城继正统之位</i>
You will marry a suitable woman
你会娶一个合适的女人…
and father children named Lannister.
生一个孩子叫兰尼斯特
And you'll never turn your back on your family again.
你不会再背弃你的家族
You have my word.
我向你保证
And you have mine.
我也向你保证
Not going well, is it?
不太顺利，是吗？
- You're going to be found guilty. - Oh, you think so?
- 你将被认定有罪？
- 噢，你觉得呢？
When you are, you need to enter a formal plea for mercy
到时候，你必须正式提出宽恕请求
and ask to be sent to the Wall.
并要求前往长城
Father's agreed to it.
父亲已经同意了
He'll spare your life and allow you to join the Night's Watch.
他会宽恕你，允许你加入守夜人
Ned Stark was promised the same thing
奈德·史塔克当时也被如此许诺过
and we both know how that turned out.
<i>我们都知道下场如何</i>
Father is not Joffrey. He'll keep his word.
<i>父亲不是乔佛里，他是言而有信的</i>
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Do you trust me?
你相信我吗？
Keep your mouth shut. No more outbursts.
你闭上嘴，别胡说八道了
This will all be over soon.
审判马上就结束了
The crown may call its next witness.
王上可以传召下一位证人
State your name.
报上名来
Shae.
雪伊
Do you swear by all the gods
你向诸神起誓…
that your testimony will be true and honest?
你的证词全是真话和实情吗？
I swear it.
我起誓
Do you know this man?
你认识这个人吗？
Yes. Tyrion Lannister.
是的，提利昂·兰尼斯特
How do you know him?
你怎么认识他？
I was handmaiden to his wife Lady Sansa.
我是他的妻子，珊莎小姐的仆人
This man stands accused of murdering King Joffrey.
这个人被指控谋杀了国王乔佛里
What do you know of this?
你知道这件事吗？
I know that he's guilty.
我知道他有罪
He and Sansa planned it together.
他和珊莎合谋
Silence!
<i>肃静！</i>
Continue.
<i>接着说</i>
She wanted revenge for her father,
<i>她要为父报仇…</i>
her mother, her brother.
<i>还有她母亲，她哥哥</i>
She blamed their deaths on the king.
<i>她怪国王害死他们</i>
Tyrion was happy to help.
<i>提利昂很乐意帮忙</i>
He hated Joffrey. He hated the queen.
他恨乔佛里，他恨太后
He hated you, my lord.
他恨你，大人
He stole poison from the Grand Maester's chamber
他从大学士的屋里偷了毒药
to put in Joffrey's wine.
放在乔佛里的酒里
How could you possibly know all this?
<i>你怎么会知道这些？</i>
Why would he reveal such plans to his wife's maid?
他怎么会让他妻子的仆人知道这些？
I wasn't just her maid.
我不止是她的仆人
I was his whore.
我是他的私妓
I beg your pardon?
<i>你说什么？</i>
You said you were his...
你说你是他的…
His whore.
他的私妓
How did you come to be in his service?
这事是什么来由？
He stole me.
他抢了我
I was with another man,
我有男人
a knight in your lordship's army.
大人您军中的一名骑士
But when Tyrion arrived at the camp,
当提利昂抵达军营
he sent one of his cutthroats into our tent.
他派他的打手到我们帐中
He broke the knight's arm and brought me to Lord Tyrion.
<i>他打断了骑士的手臂，把我带给提利昂</i>
"You belong to me now," he said.
“你现在属于我了”，他说
"I want you to fuck me like it's my last night in this world."
“我要你干我，就好像明天我就死了”
Silence. Silence!
肃静，肃静！
And did you?
你干了吗？
Did I what?
干什么？
Fuck him like it was his last night in this world.
干了他，就好像明天他就死了
I did everything he wanted.
他的要求我都满足
Whatever he told me to do to him.
不管他要我怎样
Whatever he felt like doing to me.
或者对我怎样
I kissed him where he wanted.
<i>我吻他要吻的地方</i>
I licked him where he wanted.
<i>舔他要舔的地方</i>
I let him put himself where he wanted.
<i>进他想进的地方</i>
I was his property.
我是他的财产
I would wait in his chambers for hours
我会在他房里等几小时…
so he could use me when he was bored.
等他无聊了就来使唤我
He ordered me to call him "my lion," so I did.
我要我叫他“我的狮子”，我叫了
I took his face in my hands and said,
我把他的脸捧在手里说：
"I am yours and you are mine."
“我是你的，你是我的”
Shae.
雪伊
Please don't.
别说了
I am a whore.
我是妓女
Remember?
<i>记得吗？</i>
That was before he married Sansa.
那是他娶珊莎之前
After that, all he wanted was her.
而之后，他只要她
But she wouldn't let him into her bed.
但她不让他上床
So he promised to kill King Joffrey for her.
于是他答应为她谋杀乔佛里国王
Father,
父亲…
I wish to confess.
我要认罪
I wish... to confess.
我要…认罪
You wish to confess?
你要认罪？
I saved you.
我救了你们
I saved this city
我救了这座城市
and all your worthless lives.
你们这些贱民
I should have let Stannis kill you all.
我应该让史坦尼斯把你们杀光
Tyrion.
提利昂
Do you wish to confess?
你要认罪吗？
Yes, Father.
是的，父亲
I'm guilty.
我有罪
Guilty. Is that what you want to hear?
有罪，你不是就想听到这个？
You admit you poisoned the king?
你承认毒死了国王？
No, of that I'm innocent.
不，这事，我是无辜的
I'm guilty of a far more monstrous crime.
我的罪过远比这恶毒
I am guilty of being a dwarf.
我有罪，因为我是侏儒
You are not on trial for being a dwarf.
你受审不是因为你是侏儒
Oh, yes, I am.
<i>噢，是的</i>
I've been on trial for that my entire life.
我这辈子都在因此受审
Have you nothing to say in your defense?
你没有什么要辩护的吗？
Nothing but this--
<i>只有一句话…</i>
I did not do it.
不是我干的
I did not kill Joffrey,
我没有杀乔佛里
but I wish that I had.
虽然我希望如此
Watching your vicious bastard die
<i>看着你残忍的杂种死了…</i>
gave me more relief than 1,000 lying whores.
比睡1000个婊子还舒坦
I wish I was the monster you think I am.
我希望成为你们想象中的那个恶魔
I wish I had enough poison for the whole pack of you.
我希望我有毒药把你们全毒死
I would gladly give my life
我宁可死…
to watch you all swallow it.
也要看着你们吞下毒药
Ser Meryn. Ser Meryn.
马林爵士，马林爵士
Escort the prisoner back to his cell.
把犯人押回监牢
I will not give my life for Joffrey's murder.
我不会舍命去杀乔佛里
And I know I'll get no justice here.
<i>我知道我在这里得不到公正</i>
So I will let the gods decide my fate.
因此，我请求诸神来决定我的命运
I demand a trial by combat.
我要求比武审判
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/